hello my name is in defense lawyers and
this is my third video about writers Jay
s in this video we'll take a look at
riot server-side rendering capabilities
with note if you're not already familiar
with right Jas I recommend you take a
look at my first video introduction to
ride a ass and my second video where we
cover news events and callbacks in this
video we will cover how to create a
simple express at had agreed to swig
tempering engine for express how to
render a riot egg on the server and
included in the response and how to get
our pre-rendered tagged continued to
work as expected once it's been loaded
into the browser
let's take a look at some code just like
the previous two videos will be using
the atom text senator had a terminal
window open so we can execute commands
terminal and we have a browser so we can
take a look at our completed work we're
going to be building a simple
notification so to get started we're
gonna go into a terminal execute in MGM
in it and this is gonna ask a series of
questions
pressing Enter will take the default
response and that's all we need for this
example so I'm just gonna press enter
the name the version the description and
all the way through all the options and
that's done gonna clear at the terminal
running and p.m. and it has created this
package that JSON file so we can see
that all the responses that we took the
defaults on got loaded into that file so
now we're gonna go back to her terminal
and we need to install some node modules
so I'm gonna run NPM install for express
I'm gonna pass at the same option and if
we look up at the editor here we can see
the note modules holders been created so
there's going to be an express folder in
there and I'm also gonna NPM install
Ryan began passing at the same option
and I'm gonna install swig which is the
templating engine that we're going to
use inside of our express had to create
our pages on the server side we can take
a look and see that it's been updated to
show express Ryan sway as dependencies
of this application now that we've
installed the node modules that we need
let's get started
application at JDS is going to be the
file that runs our application on the
server side is going to use express to
handle requests and respond with output
its gonna go to the page and get
rendered in the browser so we're going
to start off by declaring a few
variables so far Express is gonna make a
call to require till the Express model
saying things going to happen on the
second line with swig and then we're
going to create a variable called at
your gonna set that to equal express
that singer application needs is a way
to handle her request so an express is
gonna be called a row so we're going to
set up a round for the root of our web
application so we'll see we had at which
is referencing our express at . get you
know it's gonna respond to an HTTP get
the forward slashing single quotes there
is the route that is gonna respond to
suggest the root of our application and
then we have a function callback that
accepts your request and response object
so we need to do two more things and are
super simple express application will be
ready to go so the first thing we need
to do is inside our jet handle here we
need to respond with some kind of
content to display in the browser and
then we need to tell application to
actually listen for requests so gonna
get Adeline inside about get and then
one more at the root level of our style
so response dots and hello world is
simply going to respond to this
this request for our appt with the words
hello world
no markup new HTML that's fine the
browser will be able to handle that just
a simple test and we have a line that
says at don't listen or passing in 3000
3000 is the port there were gonna listen
with that employees can go into a second
tab and my terminal and I'm just gonna
tape in node and pass it the name of our
style at TJs and press Enter
and if we look at the terminal it
doesn't look like anything's happened
but our appt is actually run so gonna go
to the browser and go to localhost 3007
everything goes as expected will see
hello world in the browser right now we
know that's running and make a couple
changes so go back to my terminal window
wherever on that app you'll see that is
just hanging here are gonna control C to
stop yet for running and I want to
update my code file to give us some kind
of indication that the app is actually
running so in my apt out listen I can
pass an optional callback and in a call
that I'm just gonna throw in a console
that loud so that we had an indication
that the servers running and then I can
go into the terminal window and I can
write a note at Jas again and this time
you see a pauses for a second shows a
server is listening on port 3001 here
refresh everything still respond as
expected gonna go then stabbed the end
their console so now we need to tell
expressed that we wanted to use swings
are templating engine and once that's
done then we can go ahead and set up the
template and have our appt respond with
an actual HTML pitch in order to do that
we're going to go into our apt OJS file
for you to add a line at the top and
we're gonna call at . engine we're going
to pass it she knows a string and then
swing
render file and this is gonna tell
express to use wigs render file method
to render HMO now needs teller at what's
his view engine and where to get our
templates so we can add two more lines
both cause to apt outset first home or
calling you engine and passing it
HTML the second one
use directory is going to be a current
directory name / views so any data views
directory and inside that directory
we're gonna had an index HTML file
that's going to represent our index
template in our index HTML file was a
sad the court tags for an HTML file
ranch a server-side rendering and in the
body just throw in each one in there and
that's enough of a template make sure it
works so many go back to TJs we're still
responding with hello world text so
we're gonna change that respondents and
to respond or render it would simply
going to pass it
index so this is how we're gonna tell
expressed to use our index template
at startup application again note at Jas
will see the server is listening on port
3000 go back to your browser and refresh
and will see that we get back
hi nice big bold letters showing that
are each one is rendering means our
templates work so let's go ahead and
control c2 stop here and we'll keep
going with their changes we don't have a
right to get but the end goal here is to
create a red tag get it to render on the
server so that our initial page response
comes back with the fully formed HTML
output from our tag we call render with
a riot act on the server
the return value of that is going to be
in HTML string so the first thing we
need to do is make sure that we can get
an HTML string into our template output
using a variable in our appt so in our
and yet we're going to add an HTML
string as a variable so here I have RCM
pls email
wills each to
this is a test now we need to get that
into our template so it's good or
template file good index HTML and
underneath our existing h1 we're going
to add a variable in the way swing
handles variables is it encloses that in
double curly braces on either side so we
add tag content this puts a variable
called tag content in your template and
that's gonna get rendered on the serb
and now that we have that in place we
need to go back into at Jas and we need
to get that variable in toward template
what we call response not render we can
pass a second optional argument and that
second argument is an object literal not
object literal can contain all of the
variables with their corresponding
values that are gonna get injected into
our templates opacity in here and we're
gonna pass and tagged content with the
value of our sample HTML variable go
ahead and run that and see what happens
back in my terminal at Jas tells me it's
listening I can refresh the browser you
will see that our original static
content is rendered properly but are
variable is passed in and the HTML was
escaped so this is a feature to keep
things safe or make sure that you don't
allow anything malicious to be injected
and your pages but in our case we know
where the contents coming from so we're
gonna go ahead and turn that escaping
functionality off so that we can render
the HTML former variable go back into
the terminal killed that and that are
indexed I teach him know we need the
passive filter into a variable called
safe and that's gonna tell swig to
render that HTML without escaping the
tax so with dan in place let's go back
and read our application one more time
the better browser and refresh and this
time we'll see that our HTML variable
content is rendered appropriate
gonna go back into the terminal control
see the application of the terminal and
let's move on now that we have our Basic
Express application running it using the
templating engine that we selected that
can render a template we can pass in a
variable of HTML and have it rendered
properly now we need to go ahead and
create a riot back I'm gonna had a file
from my tank we're just gonna call it
hello world in the tag will wrap
everything in the tag name as I have for
simplicity's sake just to start a
go-ahead will add a message in the tag
just a simple static age too little from
the HelloWorld tak now we need to make
some updates to a.j us so we can use our
price tag on the server so the first
thing we'll do is we'll add a riot
variable with a call to require
I'm also gonna have a variable for the
tag itself so gonna create a variable
called hello and I'm gonna call require
to Hello world . tech notice that I'm
using the path in this caller acquire
because it's not in the node modules
folder so I had to tell require where to
go and find that file know when to go to
the code where we assigned our HTML
string earlier to a variable and replace
this with a call to riot render so I
create a variable tag output and I'm
gonna call right out render I get a pass
a hello which is a reference to the
variable that we created up the top and
that variables are pointing out our tag
file I don't go to update object literal
passenger render to use tag output since
that's a new variable name with that
emplacements runner at refresh the
browser and the same will see that the
page has been updated with our message
that we put in the attack when we come
back down
control Seattle occasion whether we know
that we can render attack on the server
yes it is part of our template output
wanna go update the tag and start doing
things a little more exciting than just
showing static text so go into hello
world that tag on it at the output to
reference a property owner options
object in expression just like we've
done with previous tags in our other
videos so decided to say hello comma
Hopstop first name now we need to go
back to our at the JSE's file and make
sure that that first name value get into
our tag so in the past we've done this
on the client side we've passed our
values into riot . mail for the same
thing holds true for riots at render
that we can pass at the tank to render
as well as a second argument which is an
object literal and there's hope as a
person named John and with that in place
or runner ASP and refresh your browser
will see that we get hello comment john
has an output
again . the app thank their terminal now
it's make or take a little more
interactive and go back into my tag file
an input type text name as well so gonna
add a button to go along with this input
will give it a label about eighteen and
they need to get that button on click
event so say on click equals update me
and I were gonna need some script tank
so that we can create the function for
update me inside the script tags that
anti function update name interrupting
name function is gonna take the value
added that text input had a sign a two
options that person now that we've
updated our tag to be a little more
interacted we need to compile it for use
on the client right now the server-side
rendering is not gonna load JavaScript
file into the browser in order for the
tag to continue interacting with us so
we still need to do the steps that we've
done in previous videos we run our right
command to turn this tag file into an
output JavaScript file by creating a
public directories
command and I'm going to tell it to put
my output in tags at Jas inside that
public folder will see that it created
tags ijs
I can see it that's the JavaScript
output for our hello world tank now I
need to pay at that Jas to tell it to
use that public directory that we just
created to serve static files so go into
a tie Jas
Adeline at use express that static and
will pass it the past that public
directory no need to go into our index
HTML template file we need to reference
our tags . Jas
we're also gonna need a reference to
write a essay on the client so in this
case and just going to use a CDN and
even though we're rendering are tagged
on the server that's not going to do the
client side mount that we need so we're
gonna have a set a script hangs with a
call to riot up mail now that we have
this what's going to happen is the tank
is going to render on the server is
gonna be loaded into the template can be
pants back down to the browser is part
of the response and then a right on man
is gonna run and it's gonna clear out
the options object because we're not
passing anything into it here so what we
need to do is set up some variables that
we can use on the server and get loaded
into the clients for the template so
that when riot mounts the tag Jan 12
pages loaded it's a seamless transition
and the server content stays in place
until the tags interacted with so we're
going to go into a b.j s
you're gonna add a variable called
starting name and I'm gonna give it a
different name this time just so it's
easy to see that it's working and then
we're going to update our response not
render to pass in first name calling
starting name and now I'm gonna go into
my template and I want to use that
variable in the template so this might
look a little bit confusing but what's
happening is we're calling right up on
the client we're passing an astronaut's
to tell it to load all the tags which in
our case is just the HelloWorld tag and
then we're passing an object literal
with the first name property so the
variable and double brackets is going to
be swapped out for the actual value on
the server and then when this hits the
client will be first name and then susan
in quotes so that when riot at mount
runs on the client will basically be
seamless because the server rendered
HTML will also use that same first name
value so gonna go back to apt ijs and
I'm gonna make sure that I'm using the
starting named variable in my initial
render on the server
place starting named Perry plays first
name value with starting them and that
should hook everything up so that are
tagged gets rendered on the server that
output HTML is loaded into our template
or template gets run through this week
templating engine so many variables
inside a can be swapped out on the
server sent to the client and once it
hits the client riots going to melt that
tag again and everything will function
just like it did when we did nothing but
clients i text so let's take a look at
that Sony go in and around my apt to go
back into my browser and I gotta run
this will see that are named Susan came
thru everywhere I would just make sure
this works
I can take the name into the input click
the button and it'll update and all that
interaction happens on the client just
as expected I hope you found this video
helpful you have any questions comments
or feedback please feel free to leave it
and thank you for watching